<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup Chiang Mai</title>
    <description>Startup Chiang Mai is a directory for all things startup and entrepreneurship. We also tell stories, share insights, and support community.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 12:32:34 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 12:32:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alphabet Soup: Deciphering Thailand's Digital Departments and Agencies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We may sometimes think of startups as pulling themselves up by their bootstraps, but few things in this world are created in a vacuum. When it comes to developing essential resources like talent and capital, governments play a big role in making these available and massively affect the success or failure of a startup ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emerging tech scene like Thailand, a lot of support for entrepreneurship and innovation comes from the top-down, and while &lt;a href=&quot;https://beachcity.com.au/build-entrepreneurial-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;I may have said a stern word or two&lt;/a&gt; about the effectiveness of this approach alone, there’s no denying it’s an essential component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on to learn about some of the Thai government’s digital, innovation, and economic development agencies and the role they play in Chiang Mai’s startup ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;national-innovation-agency-nia&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nia.or.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Innovation Agency (NIA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empowering Thailand’s innovation, the National Innovation Agency (NIA) has a mandate to improve Thailand’s competitiveness and promote economic restructuring. The NIA operates under the Ministry of Science and Technology and is led by the ambitious Dr. Pun-Arj Chairatana (who happens to be a Chiang Mai native - sawadee jaooo!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“NIA functions as the key engine driving national innovation by co-creation, networking, fostering, and partnering different organizations from various fields such as academic, technology, industry, finance and investment. Its main focus is on utilizing knowledge management to achieve innovation, particularly to foster “innovation on cluster platform” which uses innovation as the principal tool in improving quality of life and driving towards an increasing competitive economy.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the work they do ranges from connecting academic researchers with corporate partners to providing startup grants, NIA’s primary driver is developing strategic partnerships. By facilitating these linkages, great ideas receive the funding needed to kick things up to the next level and emerging technology has a better chance to reach the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A national body, their logo will be found on all manner of startup event banners but much of their work is also conducted via sub-agencies under their umbrella (many of which are listed below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nia.or.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nia.or.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@nia.or.th&quot;&gt;info@nia.or.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 020-175-555&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;startup-thailand&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupthailand.org/en/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startup Thailand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most visible public bodies, the aptly named Startup Thailand, are responsible for producing most of the events and media related to Thailand’s startup and innovation space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Founded as a national agency to support the startup businesses and its ecosystem based on the policy of the National Startup Committee (NSC), Startup Thailand operates under the Ministry of Science and Technology in collaboration with related organizations, helping startups to utilize local resources for their product and service development, and local employment and revenue distribution, leading to new target industries in driving the country forward.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in True Digital Park, Thailand’s (and quite possibly the world’s) largest startup campus, I was lucky enough to cover &lt;a href=&quot;https://startupthailand.org/st2019/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Startup Thailand’s annual marquee event, Startup Nation&lt;/a&gt;. With a stated aim to make Thailand a global startup destination, there is clear investment in broadcasting to the world that the country is open for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup Thailand also produce a magazine, videos and other resources aimed at educating startups and sharing ecosystem stories, primarily for Thai-language audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupthailand.org/en/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;startupthailand.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ThailandStartup&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/ThailandStartup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:startup@nia.or.th&quot;&gt;startup@nia.or.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-economy-promotion-agency-depa&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.depa.or.th/en&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Economy Promotion Agency (DEPA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/beachcitylife/videos/619696528863526/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chatting with K. Chinawut Chinaprayoon, Vice President of DEPA at Techsauce Global Summit 2019&lt;/a&gt; and found him delightfully switched on. The agency responsible for actioning the Digital Development for Economy and Society Act of 2017, this young organization works closely with startups and accelerators all well as digitally oriented SMEs to develop the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The premier Digital Economy Promotion Agency to accelerate transformation in Thailand. The agency aims to support and promote the development of digital industry and innovation, support and promote digital technology adoption which benefit the national economy, society, culture, and security.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEPA manages a startup fund, runs an IoT &amp;amp; Digital Innovation Institute, produces the annual Digital Big Bang Conference, runs coworking and event spaces and much, much more, including overseeing the Smart City initiative. In Chiang Mai, you can visit their offices east of town in the Wat Ket area or check out their coworking space at Promenada mall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a digital nomad who loves Chiang Mai, do give kudos to the incredibly hard-working &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=niKoPFxchS0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;K. Chadathacha Chantanaphan who has been the key voice in her office championing the worthiness of a digital nomad visa&lt;/a&gt;. While this initiative is unlikely to be fast-moving, there is work underway to gather data and assess the economic impact of this group (we hope to report more on this soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: 158 Thung Hotel Rd., T. Watket, A. Muang Chiang Mai 50000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.depa.or.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;depa.or.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/depachiangmai/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/depachiangmai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 053 247 282&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thailand-board-of-investment-boi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boi.go.th/en/index/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thailand Board of Investment (BOI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For entrepreneurs looking to set up their base of operations in Thailand, BOI offers incredible opportunities and perks. In addition to providing advice and incentives, they also provide a number of services aimed at making business incorporation and the usual hassles of issuing work permits easier and more streamlined, primarily through their &lt;a href=&quot;http://osos.boi.go.th/EN/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;One Start One Stop Investment Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Office of the Board of Investment is a government agency under the Office of the Prime Minister. Its core roles and responsibilities are to promote valuable investment, both investment into Thailand and Thai overseas investment. Our vision is to promote valuable investment, both investment in Thailand and Thai overseas investment to enhance Thailand’s competitiveness, to overcome the “Middle Income Trap” and to achieve sustainable growth in accordance with the sufficiency economy philosophy.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies certified by BOI receive generous tax breaks and exemptions from import duties and are also permitted to be wholly foreign-owned (so none of the typical Thai shareholder mess), to employ foreign nationals with (with no ratio of Thai employees required), and even to own land. For businesses in certain sectors, including the broad categories of technology and innovation, BOI provides further support and incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BOI office is also the body responsible for administrating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boi.go.th/index.php?page=detail_smart_visa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Smart Visa scheme&lt;/a&gt; launched in early 2019. With special visas for Executives, Investors, highly skilled Talent, and - most excitingly - Startups, they provide an easier, faster pathway for entrepreneurs to legally operate in Thailand and begin setting up new, innovative businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the original requirements for the visa left much to be desired, the BOI office have been remarkably receptive to feedback and even organized a roundtable panel in Chiang Mai to discuss which requirements and qualifications could be reviewed and revised. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aseannomad.capital/blog/thailand-smart-visa-dec-24-updates-many-fantastic-changes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated Smart Visa requirements&lt;/a&gt;, especially for the Startup category, are now much improved and worth a look for entrepreneurs and digital nomads curious about setting up a base in Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more, make an appointment or visit their offices south of town near the airport. This team are exceptionally accessible for a government office with a direct line to the Prime Minister’s office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: Airport Business Park #108-110 , 90 Mahidol Road, Haiya, Muang, Chiang Mai 50100&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://chiangmai.boi.go.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chiangmai.boi.go.th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://osos.boi.go.th/EN/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;osos.boi.go.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:chmai@boi.go.th&quot;&gt;chmai@boi.go.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone:  053-294-100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-city-thailand&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smartcitythailand.or.th&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart City Thailand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of seven in the nation, Chiang Mai was selected to be a primary testing ground for DEPA’s Smart City initiative. With access to special government grants and resources aimed at developing public facilities, promoting tourism, and enhancing quality of life, initial phases of the program will be centered around the Chiang Mai University campus and the Nimmanhaeminda neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Smart City means a city that takes advantage of modern technology and innovation to increase the efficiency of the city service and management, reduce the cost and resource usage of the target city and citizen. It focuses on good design and participation of business and public sectors in urban development, under the concept of a modern and livable city development, for people in the city to have a good quality of life and sustainable happiness. The Smart City Development Steering Committee promotes and supports operations in order to formulate a policy plan and drive the development of smart city at the local boundary level.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urban development activities that fall under the purview of Smart City range from old-school infrastructure improvements like relocating power cables and renovating sidewalks to green-tech ventures like shifting over to using electric vehicles. Some on the inside hope that the tourism-focused scope of this initiative may be broad enough to extend to the creation of a digital nomad visa, or even just easing immigration pressures to this tech-savvy community so invested in Chiang Mai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartcitythailand.or.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;smartcitythailand.or.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chiang-mai--co&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chiangmaiandco.org/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chiang Mai &amp;amp; Co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A public-private partnership between the NIA and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aristo.co.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aristo Group&lt;/a&gt;, Chiang Mai &amp;amp; Co is leading the charge to link local startups with accelerator programs, mentors and resources. One of fifteen targeted areas in which the Thai government aims to create Innovation Districts, Chiang Mai represents a unique opportunity due to its wealth of universities, cultural cache, close access to agriculture zones, and vibrant population of digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Chiangmai&amp;amp;Co founded by Startup Thailand, National Innovation Agency (NIA) and ARISTO Group. This is a partnership between the government and private company with the same goal to promote the ecosystem of the startup.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their own event/coworking space fronting Punspace Wiangkaew, Step 1 for this organization seems to be curating events and seminars (especially of note is their recently launched Startups in Residence program). Still in the works, Step 2 will be mapping and documenting all the startups and technology companies currently operating in Chiang Mai (great minds think alike!). With ties to the major government agencies, Chiang Mai &amp;amp; Co aims to feed data from program and grant applications into a central database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiang Mai &amp;amp; Co also provides business and consultancy services, including helping interested startups and entrepreneurs apply for the Smart Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Chiangmai%26Co/@18.7931375,98.9866337,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0xe73a5eb539d4b0bf!8m2!3d18.7931375!4d98.9866337&quot;&gt;Wiang Kaew Rd, T. Si Phum, A. Muang Chiang Mai 50200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://chiangmaiandco.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chiangmaiandco.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/ChiangmaiCo/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/ChiangmaiCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@chiangmaiandco.org&quot;&gt;contact@chiangmaiandco.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of technology is incredibly fast moving. While Thailand’s startup scene is only around five years old, the level of investment and action on the part of the government indicate that Thailand 4.0 is not just talk and PR. It will certainly be interesting to see how these agencies and projects shape Chiang Mai’s startup ecosystem in the months and years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks are in order to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/makerspaceth/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nati Sang of Makerspace&lt;/a&gt; for the background to get this piece started, and to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aseannomad.capital/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Munly Leong of Asean Nomad&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beachcity.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BeachCity Media&lt;/a&gt; for facilitating connections that led to the insights captured above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thai-government-agencies-startups</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thai-government-agencies-startups</guid>
        
        
        <category>resources</category>
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem</category>
        
        <category>Visa</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Four Coworking Spaces to Host Your Next Event At</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for a venue for your next meetup, mastermind or shindig? While there’s plenty of big venues and conference spaces available for hire and god knows how many cafes and bars, you might think about collaborating with some of these community-minded venues to host your next event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By day a cafe and great place to work, by night, a swanky party venue. Some of Chiang Mai’s best coworking spaces might surprise you with the transformations they make when the sun goes down. If you’re looking for a place to host your next event, whether that’s a small talk or meetup or even a full-blown party, here are a couple venues you might consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buristro-bar--cafe&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BuristroBarAndCafe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Buristro Bar &amp;amp; Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A longtime supporter of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ChiangMaiEntrepreneurs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chiang Mai Entrepreneurship Association&lt;/a&gt;, this cafe-slash-coworking space is connected to a stylish boutique hotel a hop and a skip away from the trendy neighborhood of Nimmanhaemin. A day pass here gets you wifi, a drink and access to the pool for, ya know, that work-life balance Chiang Mai’s known for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manager always seems game to collaborate on events whether it’s a pool party, meetup or seminar. With room for about 50 guests seated or up to 80 or so standing, it’s best for smaller gatherings as the acoustics are nil and the space quickly gets loud with too many talkers. The team are able to provide a microphone set up, a white board and even a projector if you need it in addition to slinging lattes and tending bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?ei=Z-2qXMCKDcz-9QPpnKLwAw&amp;amp;q=buristro+bar+%26+cafe&amp;amp;oq=buristro+&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.1.0.0i20i263j0i10l9.332797.333898..334979...0.0..0.116.833.7j2......0....1..gws-wiz.......35i39j0j0i131j0i67.jv1pf1hbmRk#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Siri Mangkalajarn Rd, A. Muang, Chiang Mai 50200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BuristroBarAndCafe/&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/BuristroBarAndCafe/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 053 217 832&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heartwork-the-sharing-space&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/heartworknevergetshard/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heartwork the Sharing Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve attended raucous New Year’s parties, quality coworking events, and intimate workshops in this airy coworking space south of the Old City. Once a printing house, when the new generation of owners took over they decided to sideline a handful of the big machines in favor of creating a gorgeous coworking space (if you like pink and you like plants, then this is the space for you). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a big downstairs space suitable for large gatherings and several smaller breakaway spaces above, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/heartworknevergetshard/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heartwork&lt;/a&gt; can be flexibly set up for a number of uses whether you’re aiming for a social event or to create a learning atmosphere. Bonus: if you need graphic design work done and to print out fliers and tickets, just step into the adjacent print shop and you’re all sorted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=heartwork+the+sharing+space&amp;amp;oq=heartwork+the+sharing+space&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i60l3.3743j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;196/1-2 Kampangdin Rd, Tambon Hai Ya, A. Muang Chiang Mai, Chang Wat Chiang Mai 50100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/heartworknevergetshard/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/heartworknevergetshard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 053 208 668&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cube-no-7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cubeno7/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cube No. 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quirky little warren of offices and workspaces tucked away in Sirimankalajarn (which seems on its way to becoming an unofficial tech hub of the city, albeit a small one) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cubeno7/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cube No. 7&lt;/a&gt; houses a coworking cafe and offices for some local software companies. Given the people who frequent the space, it has naturally become host to a number of events largely catering towards the developer and crypto communities (sidenote: if you’ve ever wanted to see a Bitcoin ATM, this is the place to check one out). With small rooms which can be booked for meetings as well as a larger central space for accommodating big groups, Cube No. 7 has a nice relaxed vibe and space for you to do your thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=CUBE+No.7+Coffee+%26+Eatery&amp;amp;oq=CUBE+No.7+Coffee+%26+Eatery&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.241j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;17/1 Sirimangkalajarn Soi 7, A. Muang, Chiang Mai 50200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cubeno7/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/cubeno7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 095 696 2899&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;passion-project-the-cafe&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/PassionProjectCNX/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Passion Project The Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opened earlier this year, the team introduced Chiang Mai to their gorgeous new coworking space with a jazzy cocktail party. True to the name, the owners have poured their hearts and souls into this space and it shows. The cafe has an upper floor with soaring ceilings and big windows (get that natural light baby!) with views of the lush landscaping. Downstairs is a small but comfortable coworking area and rumor has it they are turning extra rooms off of the courtyard garden into bookable meeting spaces. The latest improvement to the space is a disco-worthy pizza oven (you’ll know what I mean when you see it) that fires &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboratively minded, it’s worth chatting with the owners here if you’re looking to host an event. With many zones to wander around in, Passion Project would be great for social gatherings but also a surefire hit with your mastermind group if you round them up for a session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?ei=Xe2qXK_pAdve9QOUyZbQBw&amp;amp;q=passion+project+the+cafe&amp;amp;oq=passion+project+the+cafe&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0.4310.8566..8727...2.0..0.116.2293.25j1......0....1..gws-wiz.......0i71j35i39j0i67j0i131j0i20i263j0i10j0i22i30.MpHU1Ym5xws#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;68 Santiluk, Muang Chiang Mai District, Chiang Mai 50300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/PassionProjectCNX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/PassionProjectCNX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: 092 959 1597&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to get in touch with a manager at one of these venues is probably via Facebook messenger or LINE, but there’s nothing like a face to face meeting to make a great impression. Keep in mind that when you’re hosting an event at one of these spaces you’re representing the space, the team, and asking them to put in extra work as well, so establishing a good rapport and direct line of communication will go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either I or people I know have hosted events at all of these spaces for free or in exchange for services, but keep in mind this might not always be the case. If you want to take over and ask them for help and resources, make it worth their time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been to events at these spaces? What did you think? What other some other great spaces you’ve attended events at? Comments and additional suggestions are highly welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-coworking-free-event-space</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-coworking-free-event-space</guid>
        
        
        <category>resources</category>
        
        <category>Communities</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>spaces</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five Software Companies Leading Communities in Chiang Mai</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The open-source and highly supportive nature of the online developer community doesn’t always translate to an offline experience but Chiang Mai never has any shortage of tech meetups and talks. Some of the best are led by community-minded software companies playing a key part in establishing the city as Southeast Asia’s next tech hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you make great software, really? Without writing a textbook about it, you can boil this down to two things: great ideas, and badass developers. A healthy startup ecosystem should have heaps of both, and smart companies know that the way to find and support these is by bringing together the best and brightest to share and connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the web offers many tools for tech nerds to do this while comfortably hidden behind their laptops, a city like Chiang Mai also offers great opportunities for software enthusiasts to come together IRL (or &lt;em&gt;in real life&lt;/em&gt; for those not fluent in geek speak). Read on to get to know the software companies leading Chiang Mai’s developer scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinknet&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thinknet.co.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ThinkNET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team behind the Chiang Mai Developer Meetups, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thinknet.co.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ThinkNET&lt;/a&gt; is a software workshop with a big emphasis on company culture. Founded in Bangkok, the team that set up shop here in Chiang Mai were more than happy to ditch the rate-race commuter grind of the big city to embrace Chiang Mai’s more laidback lifestyle. ThinkNET go all out with the Chiang Mai Develop Meetups, organizing more than two-hours worth of workshops and presentations on everything from the newest open-source tools for software architects, to how teams can learn through design thinking or pair programming. Run primarily in Thai (though half the powerpoints are done entirely in English) the events are open to developers of all backgrounds as well as those who are looking to dip their feet into programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iglu&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iglu.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iglu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not a software company per se, digital outsourcing solution &lt;a href=&quot;https://iglu.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iglu&lt;/a&gt; tout community as one of the best reasons for developers and other digital workers to become members. They put their money where their mouth is by sponsoring and hosting a variety of events serving their membership as well as Chiang Mai’s many other remote workers and the community at large. Whether you’re tagging along to the annual company retreat, attending a fundraiser helmed by their exuberant head of communications, or learning about bio-hacking at a member-organized workshop, you can be sure that an Iglu event will be quirky, fun and well attended by top-class digital professionals from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;artisan-digital&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://artisan.co.th/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Artisan Digital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded by one of Chiang Mai’s most well connected tech-dudes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ChiangMaiEntrepreneurs/photos/a.235733746973347/336577546888966/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Chiang Mai Entrepreneurship Association’s very own Toi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://artisan.co.th&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Artisan Digital&lt;/a&gt; create digital experiences and software products worthy of Chiang Mai’s reputation for care of craft. With a stated mission to “make our home the new digital hub,” they keep close ties with Chiang Mai University’s Computer Sciences Department, Bangkok-based startups, corporate VCs and the larger Thai developer community. While they do on occasion invite the community into their cozy Sirimankalajarn office, you’ll more often see their team helping run things behind the scenes at other’s tech events and their logo emblazoned as a sponsor for all things startup in Chiang Mai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buzzwoo-asia&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzwoo.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Buzzwoo Asia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A German software outfit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzwoo.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Buzzwoo&lt;/a&gt; have had a branch in Chiang Mai for nearly a decade and in that time have earned themselves a reputation for being a great place to work. With a mixed Thai and international team, they do a lot to bring people together in-house and facilitate connections, and regularly extend invitations to Chiang Mai’s developer community to learn and grow with them. With events hosted almost every month, attendees are invited to “come for the talk, stay for the networking” and meet to discuss topics like Docker best practices, cool applications for AI and trends in the internet of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nextzy-technologies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nextzy.me/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nextzy Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever peeked into their offices at Cube 7 Coworking, you might get a bit of college dorm vibe, but this Bangkok-born software company is creating apps and software for major Thai corporates like AIS, True and Dhipaya Insurance. The Chiang Mai team host regular meetups around town and also bring developers together for hackathons, pool parties and flash talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a village, and putting Chiang Mai on the map as a tech tour de force will require companies and organizations to serve more than just themselves. By making the city a great place to work for their own teams and also supporting Chiang Mai’s developer community at large, these software houses are setting a great example for what it takes to build an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to find out about upcoming events from these supportive ecosystem players is to stay tuned to updates on each company’s Facebook page, but there are also a couple of Facebook groups you’ll often see these events posted in in. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/184800808563484/events/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CNX Community of Practice&lt;/a&gt; for events and learning opportunities for local developers or join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/cmnomads/events/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chiang Mai Digital Nomads&lt;/a&gt; group for events geared towards digital nomads and remote workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which company’s events have you attended before? Are there other Chiang Mai based software companies you see as leading the charge? Who do you wish would put on another event soon? Please share your thoughts in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-software-companies-with-communities</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-software-companies-with-communities</guid>
        
        
        <category>resources</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        <category>Software Companies</category>
        
        <category>Communities</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Co-More, Chiang Mai's Collaborative Spaces</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Where do you go when you need to get shit done or start a new business, but you don’t have all the tools and resources you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiang Mai’s many coworking spaces and outlet-rich cafes are undoubtedly one of the reasons the city is so popular with digital nomads. These hubs provide the three amenities that any entrepreneur or digital professional needs to succeed: lightning fast wifi, bottomless caffeine, and most importantly, talented people to mingle with and learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the digital realm, however, sharing resources can also benefit other types of entrepreneurs and Chiang Mai is seeing a growing number of collaborative spaces that cater to the needs of these other creative classes. By providing amenities and resources that might typically be beyond the budget of a bootstrapping entrepreneur, these shared spaces support the growth of diverse new businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;makerspace-thailand&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/makerspaceth/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Makerspace Thailand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First on the list, if you don’t already know Makerspace Thailand, then you might be acquainted with one of their successful spin-off ventures, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://airtricorder.com/&quot;&gt;Air Tricorder&lt;/a&gt;. Located next to Punspace Coworking’s Tha Pae location, this collaborative workshop comes equipped with all that the modern inventor needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 3D printers, CNC machines, laser cutters, a fully stocked workshop of power tools, and more, this is a coworking space that encourages you to bring your creativity to life. Founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chiangmaicitylife.com/citylife-articles/makerspace-the-future-will-be-open-source/&quot;&gt;Nati Sang&lt;/a&gt; is a former Silicon Valley IT professional who aims to support what he believes is an inherent strength of Thai creatives, the ability to work with their hands. For that reason, his member subscriptions are accessibly priced and the space fosters connections between local Thai and international talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a newbie looking to learn about tooling and manufacturing, the Makerspace team are happy to show you the ropes, from how to design CAD drawings to mastering 3D printing or going to town with a table saw. Need to refine your prototype before launching a Kickstarter campaign? This is the place to do it in case, you know, you didn’t bring your whole toolshed with you when you decided to move to Thailand to pursue your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/PLKSnT9svB12&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7 Rachadamnoen Road Soi 4, T. Sri Phum, A. Muang, Chiang Mai 50200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/makerspaceth/&quot;&gt;facebook.com/makerspaceth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@makerspace.co.th&quot;&gt;info@makerspace.co.th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:+6652064168&quot;&gt;052 064 168&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;niramis-co-creating-space&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/niramisworkshop/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niramis Co-Creating Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located off the Canal Road southwest of town, Niramis is a co-creating space: part coworking space, part makerspace and workshop, they’re known for hosting a variety of workshops aimed at promoting business know-how and practical creative skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also offer programs aimed and children and youth, making themselves a community center which connects people beyond Chiang Mai’s typical circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Archan Naksorn has an extensive background in industrial design and used to lecture at Thammasat University in Bangkok. He opened the space in 2018 hoping to serve a diverse community and share his skills and know how with a broader audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to workspace and resources, Niramis also offers design consultations,  business mentorship and a coffee shop any bean-snob can appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/JwAowHAYBcK2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;500/58-59 Bizpoint10, Chonprathan Rd, Mae Hia, Muang, Chang Wat Chiang Mai 50100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/niramisworkshop/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/niramisworkshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:+66818106715&quot;&gt;081 810 6715&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tha-pae-co-kitchen&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/thapaecokitchenspace/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tha Pae Co-Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the premises for her Mexican-fusion joint, restauranteur and cookbook author Yaowadee Chookong moved her original business in favor of setting up Chiang Mai’s first shared kitchen space. A joint venture with other local chefs, the venue provides members with a full restaurant kitchen, accessed according to a shared timetable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For budding restauranteurs, the co-kitchen is the perfect way to start testing recipes or hosting weekly chef’s tables without committing to a full-time lease and playing hardball with the city’s rapacious landlords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiang Mai’s chefs and organic farmers have put on regular workshops and events here, exploring everything from indigenous ingredients to artisanal vegan sushis and French baking. The shared kitchen has become g a hub for culinary creativity and a space for chefs and food enthusiast to explore, learn and celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/26R8o49vAHD2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thapae Rd, Tambon Chang Moi, Amphoe Mueang Chiang Mai, Chang Wat Chiang Mai 50300&lt;/a&gt; (in the same courtyard as Tha Pae East and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/thapaecokitchenspace/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/thapaecokitchenspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weave-artisan-society&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weaveartisansociety.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Weave Artisan Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billing themselves as a “multifaceted design studio come process driven creative venue,” this collaborative space is still in the soft-opening phase, but stay tuned for exciting things to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in the historic Wua Lai area south of the Old City, this warehouse conversion sits amongst silversmith studio and antique shops in the historically significant neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They partner with and create a community for artisans to provide studio space and host workshops and events that showcase local and regional craft, design and cultural experiences which a special emphasis on the creator’s story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/TDhfrutsP9n&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wua Lai Rd Soi 3, Tambon Hai Ya, Amphoe Mueang Chiang Mai, Chang Wat Chiang Mai 50100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://weaveartisansociety.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;weaveartisansociety.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:weave.society@gmail.com&quot;&gt;weave.society@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:+66800713218&quot;&gt;080 071 3218&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces are so much more than just jumped up coffee shops or shared offices for the untethered. They’re collaborative hubs that bring together talent and ideas, two things every startup ecosystem needs to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By serving the needs of non-digital entrepreneurs, the collaborative spaces we’ve rounded up above are giving a more diverse group of entrepreneurs and creators a jumpstart and contributing to the city’s entrepreneurial ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you checked out Chiang Mai’s collaborative space yet? Have more to add? Let us know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-coworking-collaborative-spaces/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chiang-mai-coworking-collaborative-spaces/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
        <category>resources</category>
        
        <category>spaces</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
